(忆往昔)
我们不是世上唯一的猎魔人
We are not the only hunters on the planet.
猎人啊  总这么信任他人
Hunters. So trusting.
我见过很多怪物
Listen, I have seen more than my share of monsters.
真正的怪物
And I mean real monsters.
很邪恶
bad monsters.
路西法
Oh, Lucifer.
亲爱的侄子  天呐  你变化真大
Dear nephew, my, how you've changed.
我觉得你和我得好好地长谈一次
I think you and I need to have a nice, long chat.
你也许是世间万物中唯一一个
you may be the one thing in all of creation
他仍然在乎的
that he still cares about,
唯一一个能逼他现身的
the one thing that could finally make him show himself.
终于发生了
It finally happened.
什么  你这周没留堂吗
What? You didn't get detention this week?
我和杰克  我们接吻了
Me and Jackie, we kissed.
(科罗拉多州  冈尼森外)
好了  能不能别一直说他
Okay, can I stop hearing about him every two minutes now?
"你觉得他喜欢我吗"
"You think he likes me?"
"杰克看我了  我觉得他看我了"
"Jackie looked at me. I-I think he looked at me."
他绝对喜欢我
He definitely likes me.
杰西  你知道你得小心吧
Jesse, you know you gotta be careful, right?
-我又不傻  -我知道
- I'm not an idiot. - Yeah, I know,
但不光是奈德  查理那些混蛋
but it's not just Ned and Charlie and those dicks
会打你的
who'll stomp your head in.
学校的同学和镇上的人
I mean, everybody at school and in town...
他们都会欺负你的
they won't leave you alone.
好啦
Okay.
真希望我们能离开
I wish we were gone already.
你就不能撒谎说你已经18了  搞个假身份证吗
Can't you lie and say you're 18 and get a fake ID?
加州生活是很贵的
California's expensive, okay?
我们得再攒些钱
We just gotta save some more money.
你可以卖掉你的收藏
You can sell your collection.
我会的  等时候到了
I will, okay? When it's time.
野牛镍币我至少能卖九百
I can get at least $900 for the Buffalo nickel
双鹰金元能卖四百
and another $400 for the double eagle.
这是挺大一笔钱啊
That's a lot.
听着  杰西
Look, Jess...
等我一到18  我保证
As soon as I turn 18, I promise,
我们就离开这里  好吗
we're gonna get out of here, okay?
-我能看看吗  -嗯
- Can I see it? - Yeah.
给我吧
Come on.
得去钓早鱼了  是吧
Gotta go get that early morning bite, right?
等等  我得去尿尿
Hang on. I gotta pee.
马特
Matty?
杰西
Jesse!
马特
Matty!
杰西
Jesse!
杰西  杰西
Jesse! Jesse!
马特
Matty!
马特  马特
Matty! Matty!
马特
Matty!
[邪恶力量 第11季第19集]
哥们  你昨晚到现在动过没有啊
Dude, you even move since last night?
睡觉跟抽烟一样有害
Sleeping is the new smoking.
什么  才不是呢
What? No, it's not.
是久坐  久坐跟抽烟一样有害
It's sitting. Sitting is the new smoking.
不可能
That can't be right.
迪恩  我们会找到小卡的  他比看上去强壮
Dean, we'll find Cass, okay? He's stronger than he looks.
我们拿小卡赌博  现在他被阿玛拉抓走了
You know, we gambled with Cass, and now Amara has him.
她抓他是有原因的  所以他还活着
For a reason, which means he's still alive.
我接触过阿玛拉
I've been with Amara.
她跟那些大人物有梁子  上帝  路西法
Her beef is with the big guys -- with God, with Lucifer.
那些小人物  甚至是小卡这样的天使
The small fries, even an angel like Cass,
她根本不在意
doesn't even register.
如果能伤到路西法
And if it meant hurting Lucifer,
她会毫不在意杀死小卡
killing Cass would mean nothing to her.
都一周了  我们仍然毫无线索
It's been a week. We've still got no leads.
你以为我不知道吗
You think I don't know that?
那么
So...
我们再出去猎魔啊
So we get back out there.
我们继续工作  继续走动  猎魔
We get back to work. We keep moving. We keep working.
我们会碰到小卡的线索的
We'll catch a break on Cass.
肯定会  这是因果报应
We have to. It's -- it's karma.
最近我们的遭的报应都不咋地
You know, karma's been kicking us in the teeth lately.
是啊
Yeah.
那么
So...
我们就反击吧
...let's kick it back.
看  看这个
Here. Check this out.
莉比·施特劳斯
Libby Strauss.
在科罗拉多州  冈尼森附近失踪
Uh, went missing near Gunnison, Colorado.
莉比的朋友称她是被
Now Libby's friend claimed she was carried off
一个绿眼变异怪物拖走的
by a mutant creature with green eyes.
-恶魔吗  -我也这么想  但还有
- Demon? - That's what I thought, but it gets better.
这位朋友追了上去  发现了莉比
The friend chased after 'em and she found Libby,
但她已经不是莉比了
only it wasn't Libby anymore
因为她现在也变成了绿眼变异怪物
because now she, too, is a green-eyed mutant.
-恶魔换身体  -想知道只能去看看
- Demon swap suits? - Only one way to find out.
你们有多少失踪人口
How many missing do you have?
六个  都发生在这48小时内
Six, all in the last 48 hours.
一个接一个地失踪的
They're disappearing one by one.
好  那先说莉比·施特劳斯吧
Okay, uh, let's start with Libby Strauss.
据我所知  她不是本地人
I understand that she was from out of town.
她和朋友是图森市来的
Uh, she and a friend were visiting from Tucson.
莉比是最先被报告失踪的
Libby was the first reported missing.
其他的都是本地人
But all the rest have been local?
-是的  -有线索吗
- All residents. - You got any leads?
唯一的目击者是那个朋友
The only eyewitness I have is the friend.
但不是非常可靠
Not the most reliable source.
为什么
Why is that?
她和莉比当时在进行
She and Libby were on the last legs
大麻品尝巡游  已接近尾声
of their cannabis tasting tour.
我询问她时  那姑娘身上还散发着烟呢
Fumes still coming off the girl when I questioned her.
嗑药之旅啊
A trippin' trip.
这种怪事此前发生过吗
Have you had anything odd like this happen around here before?
27年前
27 years ago.
十几个居民失踪了
About a dozen residents went missing.
再往前27年  有8人失踪
27 years before that, another 8 disappeared.
都是在几天之内吗
All within the same time frame? Couple days?
而且都是当年的这个时候
Same time of year, too.
失踪事件最早能追溯到什么时候
And how far back do the disappearances go?
就这么久  小镇是50年代才建立的
That's it. The town's only been here since the '50s.
原本是处女林地  发现了煤才被开发
It was all virgin forest till they found coal here.
那人们是如何解释失踪事件的
So then how do people explain the missing?
无法解释
Mostly they don't.
这小镇人口流动
People come and go in this town.
我也就来了两年
I've only been here two years, myself.
有些老居民自有说法
There are some old-timers with their theories.
比如
Such as?
小镇是建在印第安土著的坟场上
Town's built on an Indian burial ground.
森林居民气我们偷他们的煤
Forest folk are pissed because we stole their coal.
你怎么看
And what's your take?
我们是个小镇
We're a small town.
人们会感到厌倦  从而离开
People get bored, they get fed up, they leave.
一旦有人离开  就像逃狱一样
Once a few get free, it's like a jail break.
会激励其他人
Encourages the others.
精确地每隔27年吗
Every 27 years like clockwork?
老实说  我只能顾及
Honestly, I-I'm just focused on
眼下的失踪者
the missing that I have right now.
你们可以去翻阅案卷
You're welcome to take a look at the files,
跟目击者谈话
talk to the witness.
我还得去安抚慌张的居民
I've got panicked residents I need to talk down.
-好  -当然
- Right. - Sure.
这里怎么回事啊
What the hell is going on here?
不知道
No idea.
不管是什么  它定居在这里了
Whatever it is, it's moved in.
或者说是老再来
Or keeps coming back for seconds.
好了  我去看看其他失踪者的报告
All right, I'll go check the reports on the other missing.
那我就去跟大麻女谈了
I guess that leaves me Ganja Girl.
你会说我是看到了幻觉
You're gonna say I was hallucinating.
大麻里有迷幻药什么的
The weed was laced with PCP or something.
没事  科瑞  告诉我你都记得什么
It's okay, Cori, just -- just... tell me what you remember.
什么怪事都可以告诉我
And nothing is too strange or weird to mention.
带走莉比的东西
The thing that took Libby
一丝不挂  很苍白
was naked and pale.
但眼睛不是
Except for the eyes.
我发誓  眼睛闪过了一下绿光
I swear to God, they flashed green for a second.
而且它周身完全没有毛发
And it didn't have any hair. Anywhere.
样子像个男人
It was shaped like a man.
或是女人
Or was it a woman?
是男是女
Was it a man or a woman?
它没有
It didn't have a...
-老二吗  -什么都没有
- A penis? - It didn't have anything.
你是说它没有家伙事
What, you're saying it was junkless?
完全没有
Completely.
好吧
Okay, uh...
你还能记得什么其他怪事
anything else unusual you can remember?
声音  气味
Sounds? Smells?
声音有
Definitely sound.
我发现莉比时
When I found Libby,
她就站在那里
she was just standing there...
浑身发抖
shivering, shaking.
好恐怖啊
It was creepy.
莉比
Libby?
发生了什么事
What happened?
那不是莉比了
It wasn't Libby.
我不知道那是什么
I don't know what it was.
那个嗡嗡声  是从她体内传出的吗
The buzzing... was coming from her body?
那东西偷袭了我们之前
We heard the same sound
我们也都听到了那个声音
right before that thing jumped out at us.
绿眼  嗡嗡声
Green eyes, buzzing.
光是大麻是不会制造那样的幻觉的
Weed alone doesn't conjure up that kind of scenario.
是吧  萨姆
Isn't that right, Sam?
我当时才18
Dude, I was 18.
-罪人  -那是大学
- Sinner. - It was college.
而且可能根本是牛至叶
It was probably oregano anyways.
-真叛逆  -你个二货
- Rebel. - You're an idiot.
我也什么都查不到
Look, I'm coming up empty also.
没有生殖器和绿眼抖动都查不出什么
Uh, nothing on Junkless or the green-eyed shaker.
是没下体转化了莉比吗
So we think Junkless turned Libby?
等等
Hold up.
我们不会把这玩意叫做"没下体"吧
We're not actually gonna go with "Junkless" on this, are we?
这对我们来说都刷下限了
Dude, that's a new low, even for us.
反正是出事了  眼睛  嗡嗡声
Well, something happened. You got the eyes, the buzzing.
是啊  这绝不是巧合
Yeah, I know you're right. That can't be a coincidence.
看  我发现了这个
Uh, here, I found this.
89年的治安官  科克伦
The, uh, the sheriff who was here in '89, Cochran.
这是他的笔记  没提到嗡嗡声
Those are his notes. There's no mention of buzzing.
但他似乎原本要查出几宗失踪案了
But he seemed to be closing in on some of the missing,
然后他的笔记突然就没了
and then his notes, they just kind of abruptly stop.
他也走了吗
He take a flyer, too?
没有  他还继续做了几个月的治安官
No. He remained sheriff for a few more months.
他最终辞职了  从此不知所踪
He ended up resigning and, uh, then he fell off the radar.
我在警局问了一下
I asked around the station,
但之后已经换过几任治安官了
but that was a few sheriffs ago.
-所以  -毫无线索吗
- So... - Nothing?
调度员认为他搬去了佛罗里达
The dispatcher said she thought he moved to Florida,
但这也查不到什么
but that was a dead end.
-这案子也啥都查不到呢  -是啊
- Kind of like this case. - Yeah.
等等
Wait a second.
89年和62年案件的大部分目击者
Most of the witnesses in '89 and '62,
都已经死了或走了
they're all dead or they've moved away,
但89年案件里  似乎还有一人没走
but there does seem to be one holdout from the '89 case.
埃塔·弗雷泽
Etta Fraser.
我们去找埃塔谈谈吧
Let's go talk to Etta.
你丈夫是89年失踪的人之一
Your husband was one of the people who disappeared in 1989.
我的第二任丈夫  还算不上
Oh, my second husband. Barely that.
皮特只跟我处了几个月
Pete only stuck around a couple months.
他是自己离开的吗
So he left voluntarily?
皮特可是到处走动呢
Pete was volunteering himself all over the place.
他失踪前
Right before he disappeared,
有人看到皮特在公共场合先后泡了
people saw Pete diddling two different women in public,
两个女人
separate occasions.
是看到他干那事了吗
You mean they actually saw him in the act?
你以为"泡"是什么意思
What does "diddling" mean to you?
皮特这人不怎么张扬
Uh, Pete was never a showman,
但显然  多萝西·基根和梅莎·彼得森
but apparently, Doris Kagen and Missy Petersen
让他显露了猪头本性
brought out the hog in him.
多萝西和梅丽莎  梅莎
Doris and Melissa -- uh, Missy --
她们同年也失踪了
they disappeared that year, too.
是啊  真是没想到呢
Oh, yeah. Surprise, surprise.
我敢拿我的按揭打赌  皮特是跟其中一个跑了
I'd bet my mortgage Pete ran off with one of 'em.
但你上报了他失踪
But you reported him as missing.
他三天没回家
Well, he didn't come home for three days.
我以为他死在外面了
I thought he was dead in a ditch somewhere.
我们很久之后才发现那些女人的事
We didn't find out about the women for a long time after.
那是
Is that...
白鼠尾草吗
is that white sage?
是啊  你挺了解草药
Yeah, you know your herbs.
你打算出行吗
You, uh, planning on taking a trip?
是的  我要去姐姐那里住几周
Uh, yeah. I'm going to stay with my sister a few weeks.
有什么特别的事吗
For any reason?
你们不会相信的
You're gonna think it's real out there.
你想象不到我们都能听到什么疯狂事
Well, you'd be surprised at the kind of crazy we hear.
好吧
Well...
皮特失踪后  我们得知了两个女人的事
when Pete went missing, and we found out about the women,
我祖母说  那是因为"啾啾"
my grandma said that he "got the chitters."
据她说
Accordg to her,
这每代人会发生一次  就在春分时节
once a generation around the spring equinox,
镇上的人会发疯
people in town start going nuts,
群交  在树林里交媾
having orgies, copulating in the woods.
然后就失踪  再也不见踪影
And then they disappear, never to be heard from again.
这倒是能解释皮特的行为
Well, that's certainly one explanation for Pete.
我一直不信她的话  但是
I never really, um, believed what she said, but...
现在又发生失踪事件了
now people are disappearing again.
她一直说焚鼠尾草  可以保护自己
She always said burn sage to protect yourself.
她为什么管这叫"啾啾"呢
So why did she call it "The chitters"?
奶奶用这个词
Oh, that was the word Gran used
形容林子里传来的声音
to describe the sound coming from the woods
群交的声音
when the orgies were happening.
就是嗡嗡声
Yeah, kind of a buzzing, rattling.
你奶奶提到过绿眼睛吗
Did your Gran ever mention something about, uh, green eyes?
有
Oh, yeah.
她说  如果你遭遇了"啾啾"
Gran said that if you got the chitters,
你会充满淫欲
you get so revved up with lust
你的眼睛会发出绿宝石的光
that your eyes would shine like emeralds.
-春分对得上  -就是昨天
- So we got spring equinox. - Which was yesterday.
群交  发出嗡嗡声的绿眼怪  听上去挺带劲
Orgies, buzzing green-eyed freaks. Sounds like a rager.
好了  我们去买半打啤酒吧
All right, let's pick up a six-pack.
-才半打吗  -随便你  去翻书吧
- Just six? - Oh, whatever. Let's hit the books.
别那么怂  这边走更快
Just don't be a wuss. It's faster this way.
而且一股尿味儿  随便了
And it smells like a urinal, but whatevs.
快走
Come on!
我们跑了  然后又一个绿眼怪
We ran, and then another one with green eyes
无端冒了出来
came from nowhere.
那是霍利斯特教练
It was Coach Hollister.
格兰特·霍利斯特吗
Grant Hollister?
他袭击了我们
He attacked us.
他有尖尖的牙
He had these teeth that were pointed.
他撕开了克里夫
He ripped into Cliff.
我能听到他的尖叫  但我跑了
I could hear him screaming, but...I ran.
他杀了克里夫
He killed Cliff.
你认得那对男女吗
Did you, by chance, recognize the couple?
是迪福兄弟之一
It was one of the Deaver brothers --
高个那个  还有里莫斯基太太
the tall one -- and Mrs. Limoski.
你确定吗
You're sure about this?
你还看到别人了吗
Did you see anybody else?
我看不清他们的脸  但我确定
I couldn't see their faces, but I'm pretty sure
巷子里还有更多人在那对男女身后
there was more of them down the alley, past the couple.
我能看到他们动来动去
I-I could see them moving around.
那对在...干事的男女
The, uh, the couple that -- that was...going at it,
像是在群交吗
would you say this was a... orgy-like situation?
我从没见识过群交
I've...never seen an orgy.
-没吗  -够了
- No? - Enough.
失陪一下
Excuse us a second.
现在有个孩子被咬掉一块脖子肉死了
I got a dead kid minus a chunk out of his neck
而那女孩说出的几个人都失踪了
and all the people that girl ID'ed are missing.
之前是失踪
Were missing.
他们现在都在乱交呢
Yeah, now they're all having sex with each other.
是啊
Then there's that.
且不说消防员罗伯
Putting aside the fact that Rob the fireman
在跟图书管理员上床
is screwing the librarian,
而我还认识他怀孕的妻子
and I am friends with his pregnant wife,
现在有两名目击者称他们看到了...什么呢
now I've got two witnesses claiming they saw...what?
我都不知该怎么说  外星人吗  在袭人
I don't even know. Aliens? Attacking people.
是啊
Yeah.
怎么回事  变质的斑蟊吗
What is this? Spanish Fly gone bad?
老实说  这我俩是没见过
Well, I can honestly say this is a new one for us.
我得去联系他们的家人了
I gotta go contact the families.
好
Right.
那么类似群交的行为已经证实了
So we have confirmed orgy-ish behavior.
-嗯  就像埃塔的丈夫  -啾啾吗
- Yeah, just like Etta's husband. - What, the chitters?
我们该去犯罪现场看看
Well, we should go check the crime scene.
刘易斯探员
Agent Lewis.
科瑞  冷静
Cori, calm down.
在哪
Where exactly?
好  我就来
All right, I'm on my way.
大麻女在歇斯底里
Ganja Girl's pretty hysterical.
说她刚看到她的朋友从林子里走出来了
Says she just saw her friend walking in the woods.
她吓得不敢去  所以
She's too freaked out to go, so...
你去  我去小巷
You go. I'll grab the alley.
好
Great.
莉比
Libby?
莉比  有很多人在找你
Hey, Libby, there's a whole lot of people looking for you.
你受伤了吗
You hurt?
没有  我很好  谢谢
No, I'm -- I'm -- I'm good. Thanks.
杰西  它应该死了
Jesse, I think it's dead.
以防万一
Just making sure.
你们是谁
Who the hell are you guys?
你不会相信的
You wouldn't believe us.
你们猎魔多久了
So how long have you guys been hunting?
一起吗  就这七年
Together? About seven years.
我们听说过温家兄弟
And we've heard of the Winchesters,
但我们听说你几年前死了
but we also heard you bit it a couple years ago.
这事说来话长
Ah, that's a long, ugly, ugly story.
萨姆
Sam, hey.
这是杰西和凯撒
Uh, Jesse and Cesar.
你们是猎人  是吧
You guys are hunters, right?
-嗯  -我们居然没碰到过你们
- Yeah. - I'm surprised we never ran into you.
我们主要在墨西哥活动
Well, we're mostly in Mexico.
有时候会去德州
Sometimes we make a run over into Texas.
好啊  小巷里没人影了
Nice. Uh, nothing in the alley, by the way.
谢谢
Thanks.
你们知道这怪物是什么吗
You guys have any idea what we're hunting?
是比森
They're called Bisaan.
是一种蝉鬼
It's a kind of cicada spirit.
我们查不到关于他们的传说
We couldn't find any lore on 'em.
很少见  至少在美国很少见
They're rare, at least in America.
据信他们是来自马来西亚的森林
People think that they originated in Malaysia in the forests there.
那他们在这儿干什么
So what are they doing here?
跟往常一样
What they always do.
每隔27年  他们从地下跑出来
Every 27 years, they come up from underground,
进行几天疯狂的交配
they mate like crazy for a few days.
然后这一代死掉
That generation dies off,
进入下一轮循环
and the whole cycle goes on repeat.
他们是在繁殖喽
So they're reproducing?
但这些都是小镇居民
But we're -- we're dealing with townsfolk here.
他们不是几天前才从地洞里爬出来的
I mean, they didn't just crawl out of a hole a few days ago.
这是出来的东西
This is what surfaces.
(比森)
比森自身无法繁殖
Bisaan can't reproduce on their own,
所以他们会占据人类的身体来进行交配
so they take over a human body to do the deed.
他们从嘴巴进去
They enter through the mouth,
就像寄生蟹爬进壳里
like a hermit crab climbing into a shell.
但他们不管那个驱壳是不是空的
Only they don't care that the shell's not empty.
那没下体能解释了
Well, that explains Junkless.
-那嗡嗡声呢  -他们的沟通方式
- What about the buzzing? - It's how they communicate.
是求偶信号
It's a mating call.
你
And you, um...
靠砍头杀死他们
kill them by taking off their heads, I see.
似乎这样就行了
Seems to do the trick.
你们怎么会如此了解这些东西
How do you guys know so much about these things?
一个比森27年前掳走了我哥哥
One of them took my brother 27 years ago.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
我等了很多年
I've been waiting years
等着再回来向他们寻仇
to come back and have this shot at them.
希望你们理解
So I hope you understand,
我得拜托你们别插手
I'm gonna ask you two to take a step back from this one.
跟我们说说  你们都去过哪
Well, catch us up. Where have you guys been?
树林  他们在那儿交配
In the woods, where the action is,
寻找他们的窝  还要救你
looking for their burrow and saving your ass.
怎么了
What?
我们待在林子里的原因之一
Well, one of the reasons we've been holed up in the trees
是杰西恨镇上的每个人
is because Jesse hates the town and everyone in it.
因为他们无知又无用
Because they're ignorant and useless.
他们27年前就不相信我
They didn't believe me 27 years ago,
他们现在也不会信
they're not gonna start now.
不跟进镇上的线索太愚蠢了
It's boneheaded not to be following leads in town.
没人拦着你去找
Hey, nobody's stopping you from talking to
那群疯子问话
the whole box of crackers.
你们像兄弟一样吵嘴
Ah, you guys fight just like brothers.
简直赶上我们了
Almost as bad as us.
其实
Well...
更像老夫老妻
it's more like an old married couple.
是啊
That's...
你们...
So...
-是啊  -好吧  这样啊
- Yeah. - Okay. That's...
跟猎人结婚是什么体验
What's it like settling down with a hunter?
又臭又脏
Smelly, dirty.
对安全格外担心
Twice the worrying about getting ganked.
杰西  你是本地人
Jesse, you're from here.
你知道89年负责办案的
Do you know anything about the sheriff, Cochran,
科克伦治安官吗
who worked the case back in '89?
那混蛋根本没用
That son of a bitch was incompetent.
他多年前隐居了
He shut himself away years ago.
你知道他在哪吗
Do you know where he is?
跑了
Turned tail,
跑去了隔了几个镇的山林里
ran off into the hills couple towns over.
隐居
Lives like a hermit.
你能带我们过去吗
Can you take us there?
他当时似乎找到了一些失踪者
It seems like he was honing in on some of the missing.
我们得找到窝
We need to find the burrow.
杰西  我们在林子里转两天了
Jess. We've been beating around the woods for two days.
他们就在那里  你看到足迹了
That's where they are. You saw the tracks.
我可以继续自己找
I can keep searching on my own.
我们要没时间了
We're losing.
我跟你走吧
Why don't I go with you?
我们从我遇袭的地方找起
We'll start where -- where I got jumped.
好
Okay.
这些东西还会待多久
How long do we have before these things are gone?
我们今晚就得找到窝
We gotta find the burrow tonight.
到明天  比森就会回到地下  渐渐死掉
By tomorrow, the Bisaan will be underground, dying.
别想找到他们和他们的卵了
Won't be able to find them or their eggs.
杰西就又得再等27年
And Jesse will wait another 27 years.
我们现在是四个人了
Well, there's four of us now.
我们能干掉他们的
We'll smoke those sons of bitches.
是啊  如果我们找不到  他会痛苦死
Yeah. It'll eat him alive if we don't.
看着别人经历这种痛苦很难吧
It's hard to watch someone go through that, isn't it?
是啊
Yeah.
我自己没有兄弟姐妹
I never had a brother or a sister,
但我见识过很多次
but I've seen it over and over,
小孩子失去所爱的人
when someone loses someone when they're young.
那种伤痛无法愈合
It never heals over.
是啊
No, it doesn't.
疯狂的是
And the insane thing is,
这些年来  你见过多少猎人
how many hunters have you seen over the years
得以复仇
get their revenge?
-不多  -我也是
- A few. - Yeah. Me, too.
他们永远好不起来  是吧
And they are never fixed, are they?
是啊
No, I guess not.
但你还是得帮他复仇
But you gotta help him get that revenge anyway.
我到处找马特  找了大概
I must've stumbled around searching for Matty,
10  20分钟
10, 20 minutes.
我吓得浑身发抖
I was shaking and panicking.
叫自己集中注意力  找到他
Told myself I had to focus, find him,
我找到了
and I did.
他的绿眼睛盯着我
Those green eyes staring at me.
那不是人
It wasn't human.
我跑了  没有回头
I took off, didn't look back.
之后你再没见过他吗
You never saw him again after that?
镇上的人  包括我妈
Everybody in town, including my mom,
都以为他是被变态掳走了
thought some pervert had taken him.
她崩溃了  以泪洗面
She was falling apart, crying.
质问我怎么不记得那人的样子
Why didn't I remember what the guy looked like?
为什么要编造谎言
Why was I making up this lie?
-她还住这儿吗  -能搬走时就跑了
- She still live here? - Moved as soon as she could.
一直觉得我当初该做点什么
Still thinks I should've done something.
救他  大家都那么说
Saved him. Everybody did.
他们无法接受你哥哥
They couldn't accept that your brother
是被怪物带走了
was taken by a monster, huh?
他们不能接受的东西有很多
They couldn't accept a lot of things.
但马特接受我
But Matty did.
他是个好哥哥
He was a great brother.
-你没事吧  -上
- You good? - Go!
我不管你是不是联调局
I don't care if you're FBI or not.
那都是30年前了  我什么都不记得了
It was 30 years ago. I don't remember a damn thing.
只知道我们没找到他们
Except we never found them.
其中一个失踪者是个16岁的男孩
Yeah, well, one of them was a 16-year-old boy,
那是我哥哥
and that was my brother.
那年有很多人失去了家人
A lot of folks lost family that year.
你没帮上任何人  是吧
And you didn't help a damn one of them, did you?
杰西
Jesse...
科克伦先生
Mr. Cochran,
我们来是因为又有人失踪了
we're here because more people have gone missing.
案情一样
The same MO.
不
No.
不  结束了
No, it's done.
都结束了
It's done.
凯撒
Cesar?
你跟丢了吗
You lost it?
没有  我跟着它  看到了它去了哪
No. No, I followed it. I saw where it went.
我好像找到窝了
I think I found the burrow.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
我想那就是他袭击你的原因
I think that's why he attacked you.
他是在保护
He was being protective.
-保护什么  -雌虫  和窝
- Of what? - The females, the burrow.
有道理  他们这会儿得开始产卵了
Oh, that makes sense. Must be laying their eggs by now.
你没事吧
You gonna be all right?
嗯  我们去哪
Yeah. Where are we headed?
-可挺远  -没事
- It's a hike. - That's okay.
我想打给萨姆  但没信号
I tried to call Sam. There's no service.
你觉得一窝虫子都在那儿吗
Do you think the whole brood's there?
-如果走运的话  -走吧
- If we're lucky. - Let's go.
好
All right.
好吧  这样
Okay, I'll tell you what.
把名片留下
Leave me your card,
如果我再想起什么来  我会打电话的
and if anything comes back to me, I'll call.
科克伦先生  你没有电话
Mr. Cochran, you don't own a phone.
听着  我们所求不多
Look, we're not asking for a lot.
请把你知道的说出来
Just please tell us what you know.
我找不到他们
I couldn't find them.
这怪我
So that's on me.
我一直没缓过来
I never recovered from it. I...i...
所以我买下了这一小块天堂  安心生活
So I bought this little slice of heaven and made my peace.
希望你们比我走运
I wish you all better luck.
乔  求你
Joe...please.
我哥哥被劫走时我才12
I was 12 when my brother got taken.
我对那天的失去一直无法释怀
I never got over what I lost that day,
这世上我最爱的人
the one person in the whole world I loved the most.
好吧  我就说一次  你们该走了
Okay, I'm only gonna say this once. It's time for you to go.
听着  我们知道是什么劫走了杰西的哥哥
Listen, we know what took Jesse's brother,
还有当时和现在失踪的其他镇民
and what took all the townspeople then and now.
杰西当时还是孩子
You know, Jesse was only a kid at the time,
但他说的是实话
but he was telling the truth.
劫走他们的不是人类
What took these people was not human.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
我们就是干这个的
It's what we do.
我今天看到了其中一只怪物
I saw one of the creatures today.
我知道她是个怪物
I knew she was something.
但我不知道是什么
I didn't know what.
我89年追踪到了一个怪物
I tracked one of those things down in '89.
那怪物病了  就要死了
It was sick and dying. I...
我跟着它回到了它的...巢穴吧
I followed it back to its -- it's lair, I guess.
我女儿也在
My daughter was there.
几天前  她离家去上学
Couple of days before that, she had left to go back to school.
我
I...
我不知道发生了什么
I don't know what happened.
但她成了怪物之一
But she was one of them.
等等  你没有上报她的失踪
Wait a second. You never reported her as missing.
我知道她在哪
I knew where she was.
所有那些失踪者  都零零散散地横尸在那里
All the missing people were... scattered all around, dead.
我觉得是她和那另一个东西把他们杀了
I think she and that other thing had killed them.
我想
I tried...
我想跟她说话
I tried talking to her,
但她像疯狼一样袭击了我
but she attacked me like some kind of rabid wolf.
她牙齿尖利
Teeth like thorns.
我杀了她
I killed her.
你个混蛋  你一直知道
You son of a bitch. You knew the whole time!
你知道他们在哪  却看着大家受折磨
You knew where they were when everybody was suffering.
我也不好受
I was suffering, too!
杰西  冷静
Jesse. Hey, hey. Hold on. Hold on.
你以为会有人相信我吗  怪物
You think anybody would've believed me?! Monsters?
你还说我在编故事
You told me I was making it up!
我们本可以一起告诉大家  找到他们
We could've told people together, found those things.
他们都已经要死了
They were already dying.
所有失踪者都死了
All the missing people were dead.
不
No.
你是不想说出自己的孩子也是其中一个
You didn't wanna say that your kid was one of them --
一个怪物  而且是你...
a monster -- and that you...
杀了她
killed her.
-杰西  -你杀了她
- Jesse. - You killed her.
杰西  停下  够了
Jesse, stop. Stop.
你做了什么
What did you do?
你就把她从你的生命中抹除了吗
What, did you just erase her from your life?
装作她只是去了别的地方
Pretend that she just went away somewhere?
是啊  最好埋在心底
Yeah, better to bury it.
把一切都藏起来
All of it.
我们让镇上的人以为
We just let the townspeople think
他们所爱的人是逃去过上了...
their loved ones had run off for a...
美好的新生活
big, bright life.
她当时在哪  你是在哪找到她的
Where was she? Where did you find her?
在泰勒溪旁边
By Taylor Creek.
老唐纳利矿井
The old Donnelly mine.
走吧
Come on.
丢刀的感觉真不爽
I hate it when I lose my blade.
是啊  你刚刚本可以帮帮忙的
Yeah. You could've jumped in anytime.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这是个产房/地铁站
It's a maternity ward/ subway station.
那个洞  我觉得是条隧道
That hole -- I think that's a tunnel.
一定是通到地面的
That's gotta go topside eventually.
母亲已经死了
Mothers are already dead.
那些雄性不是在保护她们
Males weren't protecting them.
他们是在保护卵
They were protecting the eggs.
幼虫在孵化之前一定要在肚子里待很长时间
They must gestate inside for years till they hatch.
是啊  但这些待不久了
Yeah, well, these aren't.
我车里有5加仑的汽油
I got about 5 gallons of gasoline in the car.
我去把车开过来
I'll go pull her around.
你们找到窝了吗
You guys find the burrow?
-他们在哪里  -在矿井里
- Where are they? - They're in the mine.
别担心  他们不会出来了
Don't worry. They won't be coming back out.
我们只要把卵处理掉就行
We just gotta take care of the eggs.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事  终于要结束了
Hell, yeah. It's finally over.
你想去把他们解决掉吗
You wanna finish them off?
给他点时间吧
Let's give him a minute.
天呐
Aw, jeez.
各位
Hey, bro.
我们找到马特了
We found Matty.
天呐
Oh, jeez.
Oh, god.
我们会好好安葬他的
We'll give him a proper burial.
那其他人呢
What about the others?
别担心  我们会...
Don't worry. We'll, uh...
我们会搞定的
we'll take care of it.
你知道吗...
You know...
以前每次你和老爸丢下我去猎魔
whenever you and dad used to leave me to go hunting
我好一阵都听不到你们的音讯
and I -- and I wouldn't hear from y'all for a while,
我...
I, um,
我总想一定是有吸血鬼  或者法国狼人
I was always sure that some vamp or rugaru
或者其他的什么...
or take your pick...
我总觉得你们一定是被什么怪物干掉了
I always figured one of them finally got ya.
我开始想我该怎么办
I tried to think of what to do,
下一步该怎么做
you know, the next step to take.
我总是很迷茫
I was just lost.
但我们每次都回来了
We came back, though, every time.
是啊
Yeah.
再说了  看看杰西  他不也挺过来了
And look at Jesse. I mean, he turned out all right.
他俩很搭
They're a good team.
的确
They are.
我之前在想
I was thinking,
也许他们能帮帮我们  对付阿玛拉
maybe they could give us a hand with Amara,
找小卡
you know, with Cass.
新视角
Fresh eyes.
多点人手也是好事
Could use the extra muscle, too.
是啊
Yeah.
你成功了
You did it.
是我们成功了
We did it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
幸亏你们有灭火器
You know, it's a good thing you guys had that fire extinguisher.
是啊  有那么一瞬间
Yeah, for a second there,
我以为整个矿都要烧起来了
I thought the whole mine was gonna go up in flames.
你就喜欢那样
Yeah, you loved it.
就像27年的生日和圣诞节
Like 27 birthdays and Christmases
都融在那一团火里了
all in one fireball.
在洞里待了大半宿
Well, you're awfully upbeat
你心情还真是愉悦啊
for a guy who spent half the night in a cave.
那是因为我们之前约定好了
That's because we had a deal.
等我们完成了这次猎魔
When we finished this hunt,
假如我们抓住了他们
if we caught 'em,
我们就退出江湖
we hang up our spurs.
真好
Nice.
除非你们需要帮助
Unless your hides need saving.
不
No.
不用了  我们很好
No, we're all set.
那么你们打算干什么去
So, uh, what's freedom look like?
新墨西哥州的一小块地
Nice little spread in New Mexico.
我们分期付款好几年了
We've been paying on it for years.
但也就去住过...两次
Set foot on it about... twice?
打算养马
Gonna raise horses.
假如这事没成
And if that goes bust,
杰西之前做过急救人员
Jesse used to be an EMT.
现在我要养你了是吧
Oh, so now I'm supporting your ass?
该开始生活了
It's time to start living.
开不了口是吧
Couldn't do it, huh?
是啊  那么做不厚道
No, didn't feel right.
是啊
Yeah.
我懂你的意思
I know what you mean.
两个活着退出的猎人
Two hunters who make it to the finish line?
是啊  就别去打扰他们了
Yeah, you leave that alone.